<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Galleries on Matthias Meng Yan Wong</title>
    <link>https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Galleries on Matthias Meng Yan Wong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 21:57:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meaning-Making</title>
      <link>https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/meaning-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 21:57:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/meaning-making/</guid>
      <description>Using historical sources, I excavate the mental worlds of the past across a wide range of time.
Early modern temporality: In my PhD dissertation &amp;lsquo;The impact of the regicide of Charles I on contemporary English notions of time and the future&amp;rsquo; at the University of Cambridge, I examined the execution of King Charles I in 1649 as a moment of ideational change and adaptation. Taking a diachronic approach to periodicals like almanacs and newsbooks, I traced how ideas of time and the future evolved in response to unexpected political change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/digital-humanities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 22:25:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/digital-humanities/</guid>
      <description>Historical GIS: I work mainly with historical geographical information systems (GIS), georeferencing and performing data capture on historic maps to create a digital interactive &amp;lsquo;kinetic map&amp;rsquo;. This sequential, dynamic and interactive animation will reveals how the treaty process drove the transformation of the Northeast American political and intercultural landscape over 230 years.
Machine learning maps: I lead a collaborative project with the Alan Turing Institute to explore how we can use machine learning to automatically recognise text on pre-20th century colonial maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Humanities</title>
      <link>https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/environmental-humanities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattwong.co.uk/gallery/environmental-humanities/</guid>
      <description>Indigenous environmental research: I am Associate Editor of Cambridge Elements in Indigenous Environmental Research. It offers state-of-the-art interdisciplinary analyses within the rapidly growing area of Indigenous environmental research, and is aimed at researchers, policy-makers and NGOs. The series investigates how environmental issues and processes relate to Indigenous socio-economic, cultural and political dynamics. We invite submissions on topics like traditional ecological knowledge, resource management, food systems, and more. More details on the Series page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
